Guide to the Wanda Gifford Photographs 1948-1958
Oregon State University Libraries, University Archives
- Numbered Photographs, 1948-1957; Series I; 1946 negatives and 884 prints
  - FFA Award Members, 1154; 4x5 negative (Box 11)
    6 counts burn in faces; F8 no. 2 paper
  - Salem chapter of Future Farmers of America, 1155; 4x5 negative (Box 11)
    5 counts; F8; burn in faces
  - Future Farmers new and old officers; in hall eating, 1156; print and 2 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 11)
    burn in faces; 5 counts
  - Romona in wedding dress, 1157; 5 4x5 negatives (Box 11)
  - Salem, Oregon, scenes, 1158
    - Coca Cola bottling company, 2 120 negatives; 1158a-1158b (Box 11)
    - Oregon State Capitol building, 120 negative; 1158c (Box 11)
    - House, 120 negative; 1158d (Box 11)
    - Swimming pool, 120 negative; 1158e (Box 11)
    - Kids playing baseball, 120 negative; 1158f (Box 11)
  - Harold Domogalla, Courthouse tax office, 1160; print and 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 6, 67)
  - Harold Larson at lamb show, 2 prints and 2 4x5 negatives; 1161 (Box 6, 11)
  - Mirthful Queenie, Grand Champion Cow, owned by Wm. Frith of St. Paul. She took top honors at the Guernsey Spring Show held at the Fairgrounds, May 21, 1949; 1162; print and 4x5 negative (Box 6, 11)
  - Guernseys at show (Box 6)
  - Tulips in Elmer Worth's garden, Havenworth, 1163; 4 prints and 2 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 11)
  - Naturalization group, 1954; 1164; 4x5 negative (Box 11)
  - Smith Rock, 1165; 17 120 negatives (Box 11)
  - Millard Henney, flowers, 1166; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 11)
  - Spraying peach orchard with Cub Farmall, 1167; 4x5 negative (Box 11)
  - Car driving across a bridge, 1168; 4x5 negative (Box 11)
  - Long shot of the McCullough Memorial Bridge, North Bend, 1169; print and 4x5 negative (Box 6, 11)
  - Alsea Bay Bridge, Waldport, 1170; print and 4x5 negative (Box 6, 11)
  - Alsea Bay Bridge, Waldport, 1171; print and 4x5 negative (Box 6, 11)
  - Long shot of the McCullough Memorial Bridge, North Bend, 1172; print and 4x5 negative (Box 6, 11)
  - Shot from bridge of boat, 1173; 4x5 negative (Box 11)
  - Yaquina Bay Bridge, March 1, 1954; 1174; 4x5 negative (Box 11)
  - McCullough Memorial Bridge, looking head on, 1175; print and 4x5 negative (Box 6, 11)
  - Logs in Umpqua? River, 1176; print and 4x5 negative (Box 6, 11)
  - Car on highway, Oregon coast, 1177; print and 4x5 negative (Box 6, 11)
  - McCullough Memorial Bridge, North Bend, 1178; print and 4x5 negative (Box 6, 11)
  - Sunset on the Willamette River, Salem, Oregon, 4x5 negative; 1179 (Box 11)
  - FFA champions at corn show, Silverton, Oregon, 1180; 3 4x5 negatives (Box 11)
  - Sunset over Willamette River bridge, Center Street, Salem, 1181; 4x5 negative (Box 11)
  - Sunset on the water front, Salem, Oregon, 1182; 4x5 negative (Box 11)
  - Rosemarie and twins, 1183; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 11)
  - Larson negatives; two little girls dressed up, 1184; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 11)
  - Orchard with mountain in background, 1185; 120 negative (Box 11)
  - Large ship, 1186-1187; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 11)
  - Yaquina Bay Bridge, March 1, 1954; 1188; 4x5 negative (Box 11)
    F22 at 1/25; no. 2 paper; K2 filter
  - Yaquina Bay Bridge, March 1, 1954; 1189; 4x5 negative (Box 11)
    F22 at 1/25; K2 filter; speed graphic; s.p.p
  - Looking south from Hearts Delight; Kueny ranch, 1190; 120 negative (Box 11)
  - Sheep with lambs, 1191; 5 4x5 negatives (Box 11)
  - Bridge over river with docks, Depoe Bay, Oregon?, 1192; 4x5 negative (Box 11)
  - Rough ocean shore, 1193-1194; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 11)
  - Coastal river outlet, 1195; 6 4x5 negatives (Box 11)
  - Rocky shore, 1196; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 11)
  - Rocky shore, 1197; 4 4x5 negatives (Box 11)
  - Docks, 1198; 2 prints and 4 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 11)
  - Fishing boat at dock, 1199; 4x5 negative (Box 11)
  - Wallace Orchards, 1200; 2 prints and 5 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 11)
  - Sawtooth Range Little Red Fish Lake, Idaho, 1202-1204
    - 1202-1203, 2 4x5 negatives and 2 oversize prints (Box 11, 76)
    - 1204, 4x5 negative (Box 11)
  - Sheep on pasture near Stanley Idaho; Sawtooth Range in background, 1205; 4x5 negative (Box 11)
  - Galina Pass, Stanley Range, 1206; 4x5 negative (Box 11)
  - Big Red Fish Lake near Stanley, Idaho, 1207-1208; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 11)
  - Big Red Fish Lake near Stanley, Idaho, 1209; 4x5 negative and oversize print (Box 11, 74)
  - Snow at Mt. Hood, 1210; 30 120 negatives (Box 11)
  - Man boxing tomatoes in a packing building, 1211; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 6, 11)
  - Boxed tomatoes, 1212; print and 4x5 negative (Box 6, 11)
  - Tomato boxes, 1213; 120 negative (Box 11)
  - Apples on branches, 1214; 2 prints and 2 120 negatives (Box 6, 11)
  - Man standing at tomato filled table, 1215; print and 120 negative (Box 6, 11)
  - Tomato lined walls, 1216; print and 3 120 negatives (Box 6, 11)
  - Close up of tomato plants, 1217-1219; print for 1218 and 120 negatives (Box 6, 11)
    - 1217, 120 negative
    - 1218, print and 120 negative
    - 1219, 120 negative
  - Woman weighing tomatoes, 1220; 120 negative (Box 11)
  - Packing building, 1221; 120 negative (Box 11)
  - Tomato plants, 1222; 120 negative (Box 11)
  - Greenhouse tomato plants, 1223; print and 120 negative (Box 6, 11)
  - Early morning on desert; sage brush and Steens Mountain, 1224; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 11)
    One view using telephoto lens.
  - Row of Cottonwood trees, Steens Mountain; entrance to homestead, 1225; 4x5 negative (Box 11)
  - Hay stacks, Wild Horse Valley, Steens Mountain, 1226; 4x5 negative (Box 12)
  - Fish Lake, Steens Mountain, 1227; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 12)
    2 views
  - Rolli shots of Fish Lake, 1228; 1 print and 5 120 negatives (Box 6, 12)
  - Gate across desert toward Steens Mountain, 1229; 4x5 negative (Box 11)
  - Crossing Catlow Valle, winding road (Rolli shots), 1230; 2 120 negatives (Box 12)
  - Heading into Steens; car on road person beside it, 1231; 4 120 negatives (Box 12)
  - Water hole, Steens country, 1232; 3 120 negatives (Box 12)
    View of cattle not taken in Steens.
  - Remains of stone cabin, 1233; 3 120 negatives (Box 12)
  - Store at French Glen, 1234; 120 negative (Box 12)
  - Hearts Delight; Mary on porch over looking Steens and meadows, 1235; 6 120 negatives (Box 12)
    Kueny House (1235.2); Mary Kueny (1234.6)
  - Various images in Steens Mountain area, 1236
    - Woman holding flowers, 1236.1; 120 negative (Box 12)
    - Gate (good), 1236.2; 120 negative (Box 12)
    - Woman holding flowers, 1236.3; 120 negative (Box 12)
    - Man and woman on branch above water, 1236.4; 120 negative (Box 12)
  - Sheep shearing at Mary Kueny Ranch, Steens; Frank McElhone and Dale, 1237; 8 120 negatives and 2 oversize prints (Box 12, 76)
    Includes image of Mary Kueny watching two men shearing sheep.
  - Pioneer cabin back of Hearts Delight; note construction, 1238; 6 120 negatives (Box 12)
  - Large Juniper tree, Kueny Ranch; top of Steens, looking at Big Indian, 1239; 3 120 negatives (Box 12)
  - Mary coming in off range on horseback; dog following also herding horses, 1240; 2 120 negatives (Box 12)
    2 Rolli shots
  - Chemeketan trip to Todd Lake area, 1241; 14 4x5 negatives (Box 12)
  - Mt. Hood and Lost Lake, 1242
    - print and 4x5 negative (Box 6, 12)
    - 2 oversize prints (Box 76, *)
  - My car going around curve under overpass, showing armco guard rail, 1243; print and 4x5 negative (Box 6, 12)
  - Grand Tetons and Snake River, 2 prints and 3 4x5 negatives; 1246 (Box 6, 12)
    6 to 9 counts F11; bad negative
  - Grand Tetons and Snake River, 1247; 4x5 negative (Box 12)
    good negative
  - Hikers Paul Deuber (left) and LeRoy McDuffie (right), 1248; print and 4 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 12)
  - Woman standing next to car gazing at lake and mountain, 1249; 4x5 negative (Box 12)
  - Grand Tetons and other scenes, 1251; 5 prints, 44 4x5 negatives and 33 120 negatives (Box 6, 12)
    Includes images of mountains and lakes; farm scenes; timber carnival; and camping.
  - Smith Rock, Oregon, 1283; print and 3 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 12)
  - Sister Mountain; boat in foreground, Crawfords fishing, 1284; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 12)
  - Hood River Valley, Spring 1957; 1285; 2 prints for and 6 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 12)
    Elwood enlarger; no 3 paper; 3 1/2 counts foreground, 5 to 6 for mountain, 8 sky
  - Rolli snow shots, 1955; 1286; 15 120 negatives (Box 12)
  - White River, Mt. Hood, 1293; 4x5 negative (Box 12)
  - Mt. Hood and Lost Lake, 1294; 2 prints and 3 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 12)
  - Little house on creek being built; shows trees before Columbus Day? storm, 1299; 10 120 negatives (Box 12)
  - Sunset from Kueny Ranch, 1301; 2 120 negatives (Box 12)
  - Looking south at Kueny Ranch, taken from road, 1302; 2 120 negatives (Box 12)
  - Boy on horseback in hay field in Wild Horse Valley, 1303; print and 120 negative (Box 6, 12)
  - View from yard; Hearts Delight; Steens Mountain, 1304; 2 120 negatives (Box 12)
  - View up Wild Horse Canyon; hay stack framing picture; truck, 1305; 120 negative (Box 12)
  - Historical marker on the Bannock War, 1306; 120 negative (Box 12)
  - Cattle guard crossing in vicinity of Steens Mountains, 1307; 2 120 negatives (Box 12)
  - Figure by side of car on road looking at Diles of 2 in grove of trees; Mary Kueny?, 1308; 120 negative (Box 12)
  - Road heading toward narrow; Steens Mountian, 1310; 120 negative (Box 12)
  - Haying in Wild Horse Valley, 1311; 5 120 negatives (Box 12)
  - Growing rhododendron from seed, 5 prints (Box 6)
    Photographs submitted with article written by Wanda Gifford for Flower Grower on growing rhododendron from seed. Includes images of newly sprouted rhododendron seeds; flatted seedlings; a covered bench for sprouting seed; and Mr. Henry's greenhouse with flats of various rhododendrons. Typescript of article also included.
- Unnumbered Photographs, 1949-1958; Series II; 581 negatives and 163 prints
  Series II consists of images made by Wanda Gifford, primarily in the 1950s, that were not assigned individual numbers. The images depict similar subjects as Series I with a predominance of photographs of Salem, Oregon; the original Marion County Courthouse; churches in Salem; and family group potraits and wedding photographs. The courthouse photographs include interior and exterior views and images of offices and workers in the building. The series includes images of the construction of Detroit Dam and agriculture, especially in the Willamette Valley. Most of the items in the series are 4x5 and 120 format negatives without accompanying prints. Some of the 4x5 negatives are diacetate-based that are degraded and in poor condition. A small number (less than 50) prints do not have accompanying negatives.
  - Panoramic views of Salem bridges and other buildings, 7 panoramic 120 negatives (Box 69)
  - Automobile accident, 6 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Mary Kueny ranch?, 2 4x5 copy negatives (Box 13)
  - Ruby Hughes at Courthouse entrance, 2 120 negatives (Box 13)
  - Gladys White eats her lunch in old Courthouse, 2 120 negatives (Box 13)
  - Building on corner of Court and Commercial, Salem, Oregon, built 1886; print and 120 negative (Box 6, 13)
  - Honey Family, 6 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
    Three views of family and three of baby.
  - Mt. Bachelor; Sparks, Chemeketans, Crawfords, etc., 23 120 negatives (Box 13)
  - Front doors of the (new) Marion County Courthouse, 2 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Group dancing; Tie Lodge, Mt. Hood; showing socks, 2 120 negatives (Box 13)
  - Snow at Mt. Hood, 4x5 negative (Box 13)
  - Fern Cummings family and wedding, 13 prints and 5 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - Hood River Valley pear orchard, 3 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Canada shots: Valley of Seven Peaks and Moraine Lake, print and 3 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - Apple blossoms, 3 prints and 4 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
    no. 2202; print diagonally
  - Pet Parade, Silverton, Oregon, June 6, 1953; 9 120 negatives (Box 13)
    no. 2205
  - Timber Carnival, Albany, Oregon, July 2, 3, and 4; 23 120 negatives, 14 prints, and 6 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - Agriculture views, 2 prints and 15 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - Chemeketans outing, 8 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - New courthouse, 2 prints and 3 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - Gooseberry patch, 4 prints and 4 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - South Salem High School entrance, print and 4x5 negative (Box 6, 13)
  - Methodist Church on corner of State and Church Streets, Salem, Oregon, 1958; 3 prints and 2 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - Parade, 6 120 negatives (Box 13)
    no. 6214
  - Along a road, 4 120 negatives (Box 13)
    no. 6213
  - Chemeketans at Larch Mountain, print and 4 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
    no. 1328
  - Covered bridges, 3 prints and 4 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - Newspaper trip, 3 prints and 10 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
    Setting type and other views.
  - Pictures in and around Salem, Oregon, 8 120 negatives (Box 13)
  - Chickens near Pratum, Oregon, 2 120 negatives (Box 13)
  - Cherry blooms, 1958; 6 prints and 4 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - Bee swarm on a parking meter, 4x5 negative (Box 13)
  - Pratum Co-op and cane berry field, 3 120 negatives (Box 13)
    no. 1330
  - Trip with Francis and Bernice to coast, Timberline Lodge, and OSC Memorial Union, 11 120 negatives (Box 13)
    no. 6201
  - Artichoke field, Santa Cruz (California?), 2 120 negatives (Box 13)
  - Men on light pole, 2 120 negatives (Box 13)
  - Moore statue "Guidance to Youth," Bush pasture, 2 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
    1/50 at F16; 2 counts; 30 sky; Ansev Ardura K. double weight; side view; 3 and 100 for sky
  - Presbyterian Church in middle of Chemekata Street being moved, 120 negative (Box 13)
  - Mountain with a lake in the foreground; vertical shot, 4x5 negative (Box 13)
  - George R. Duncan photographs of 1913 trial in North Dakota, 2 4x5 copy negatives (Box 13)
  - Marion Co. Courthouse, south side on a winter day, 1951; print and 120 negative (Box 6, 13)
  - Frizelle baby, 120 negative (Box 13)
  - Hamilton baby, 8 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Skiers at Mt. Hood, March 15, 1952; 5 prints and 11 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - Capitol grounds; snow; bush in bloom, 1950; 4 prints and 18 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - Rhododendron in bloom near State Capitol, print and 4x5 negative (Box 6, 13)
  - Chemekatans gather mistletoe, Christmas 1951, 11 120 negatives and 3 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Chemekatans on Mt. Hood, March 15, 1952; 12 120 negatives (Box 13)
  - Citizenship group naturalized, 1951; 4 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Winnie baby Kathleen, 6 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Garnet Six at his desk in Old Courthouse, 120 negative (Box 13)
  - Cloud negative, 4x5 negative (Box 13)
    good; dark foreground
  - Man standing on edge of lake, 4x5 negative (Box 13)
  - Helen Roboshi at coffee counter, 3 120 negatives (Box 13)
  - Carol Canturny wedding, print and 5 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - New Marion Street bridge approach, park, etc., Salem, 7 120 negatives (Box 13)
  - Close up of boysenberry on vine, 4 120 negatives (Box 13)
    Rolli shots
  - Merl Frizzille with baby Kathy, Christmas 1951; 8 120 negatives (Box 13)
  - Methodist Church in Salem under repair, 4 prints and 4 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - Rose Howard, Rhuea Stanton, Mrs. Lindsay, 4 120 negatives (Box 13)
  - First Federal Savings building, Court Street, Salem, Oregon, print and 120 negative (Box 6, 13)
  - Marion Co. Courthouse and surrounding area, March? 1950; 5 prints and 18 4x5 diacetate negatives
    - Methodist Church from Courthouse, 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 66)
    - Woman standing in front of Courthouse vault, print and 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 6, 66)
    - Judge Grant Murphy's office? Commissioners Court?, print and 2 4x5 diacetate negatives (Box 6, 66)
    - Courthouse steps, print and diacetate negative (Box 6, 66)
      Thousands of Salem and Marion County folks have climbed these stairs in the last 75 years, since the Marion County Court House was built in 1873. Ruler shows how they are are worn and the square nails are protruding in places. Plans are in the making for a new building unless scarcity of materials prevent.
    - Woman operating microfilm? camera, 2 4x5 diacetate negatives (Box 66)
    - Feet on Courthouse steps, 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 66)
    - People working in Courthouse office, 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 66)
    - Man reviewing deed record books, print and 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 6, 66)
    - Architectural detail of windows, 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 66)
    - Two people in an office, 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 66)
    - Women working with deed books, print and 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 6, 66)
    - Women working in an office, 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 66)
    - View of outside of courthouse, diacetate negative (Box 66)
    - Man sitting in a chair smoking a cigar, 2 4x5 diacetate negatives (Box 66)
    - Public (deed recorder's?) counter, 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 66)
  - Outside of the Courthouse, print and 2 diacetate negatives (Box 6, 66)
  - Clerk's office, Courthouse, 4x5 negative (Box 13)
  - New citizens group, June 1952; 5 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Cummings family, near Greenlee, 5 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Haive portraits, 2 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Lindsay portraits at 50th wedding anniversary, print and 3 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - Newall portraits, 5 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Naturalization ceremony, taken December 1950 at YMCA Christmas party, 2 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Helen Kleighe at her microfilm machine, 1950; 2 120 negatives (Box 13)
  - A woman and girl walking through an orchard, 3 120 negatives (Box 69)
  - Cars parked under bridge ramp; people and a boat on shore of the Willamette River? near a bridge, 2 prints and 2 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - Hereford cattle Black Butte Ranch, 4x5 negative (Box 13)
  - Kathrine Jeldrick's land, D St., 4x5 negative (Box 13)
  - Pervine; Lincoln and Fairmont St. SW Corner; Billy's birthday, 6 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Hedda Swart Deaf School, 12 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - The Dalles Dam, Bridge, & Celilo Fish Fry, 1 print and 6 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - Grace Lutheran Church with pastor Oscar Enger, print and 5 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - First Presbyterian Church, 4 prints and 2 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 13)
    G filter
  - Church views, interior and exterior, 1956
    - Children and youth Sunday School classes, 12 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
    - Adult Sunday School classes, 2 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
    - Communion altar, 2 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
    - Sanctuary, print and 2 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 13)
    - Greeter at door, 2 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
    - Church building, 5 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Methodist Church, Salem, 2 prints (Box 6)
  - Detroit Dam construction
    - Secondary crushers, February 25, 1951; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous views, 3 4x5 negatives and 4 4x5 diacetate negatives (Box 13, 66)
    - Crusher, February 25, 1951; 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 66)
    - Stationary boom and powerhouse, February 25, 1951; 1 4x5 negative and 1 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 13, 66)
    - Form work on dam, February 25, 1951; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
    - Overhead cranes, February 25, 1951; 2 4x5 negatives and 1 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 13, 66)
    - Cement mixing and pouring, February 25, 1951; 3 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
    - Cooling and cement, February 25, 1951; 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 66)
    - Overall views, February 25, 1951; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous views, 1 print and 2 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 13)
      View of construction.
  - Small dam and pond built in Depoe Bay, July and August 1956; 12 120 negatives (Box 13)
    Rolli negatives
  - Old Marion County Courthouse and views of surrounding area from its roof
    - Methodist Church, 2 prints and 2 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
    - Downtown Salem, print and 3 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
    - Capitol, 2 prints and 4 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
    - Courthouse clock tower, 2 prints and 3 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
    - Second floor hallway, 2 prints and 2 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
    - Recorder's Office staff in the vault with deed books, print and 2 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
      Deputies must climb the ladders to reach the large volumes stored in the crowded vault of the Recorder's Office at the Marion County Courthouse in Salem. From left to right: Romona Evans, Salem; Virginia Gritton, Salem; and Irene Johnson, Salem.
    - Office workers, 14 120 negatives (Box 13)
    - Judge's chambers, 120 negative (Box 13)
  - County Clerk's office staff, 1950? (Box 6)
  - Fairbanks scales in Old Marion County Courthouse, print and 2 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - Marion County Courthouse built in 1873, January 10, 1951; print and 2 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - View of downtown Salem, 120 negative (Box 13)
  - Marion County Courthouse Clock close up, 120 negative (Box 13)
    print on no. 2 paper
  - Bell in Marion County Courthouse installed in 1873, January 10, 1951; 2 prints and 3 120 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - Field trip to yard of orchardist Paul Wallace, 2 prints and 9 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 13)
    Includes image of entrance garden gate and garden views. See also color transparencies.
  - Daffodils in a vase, 3 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Daffodil field, 3 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Car on a highway, 4x5 negative (Box 13)
  - Boats on a bay, 4x5 negative (Box 13)
  - Building covered in ivy, 4x5 copy negative (Box 13)
  - Two people riding horses in an arena, 4x5 negative (Box 13)
  - Children playing in a schoolyard, 4x5 negative (Box 13)
  - Back view of the Marion County Courthouse, 4x5 negative (Box 13)
  - Interior of a large building, 4x5 negative (Box 13)
  - Construction on a river embankment, 4x5 negative (Box 13)
  - Large field, 4x5 negative (Box 13)
  - Swans in a lake, 2 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Orchards, 3 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - People ice skating, 9 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Krause pigs; Jelders; pigs at fair, 10 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Odd tree in Grand Tetons, 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 6, 13)
  - Pond and berry pickers, 2 prints and 2 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - Marsch tractor; Ben Newall, 5 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Lester Erb of Albany with cow at fair, print and 4x5 negative (Box 6, 13)
    Mr. Lester Erb of Albany proudly models his Junior Champion Female, Erb Farms Petunia, at the Guernsey Spring Show held at the Fairgrounds, Saturday May 21. This same animal won first prize senior calf last year and this year she took first prize senior yearling and Junior Champion.
  - Governor McKay and Mable McKay in receiving line, 2 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Roxie Stoops' mother on left; copy of a 19th century portrait, 4x5 copy negative (Box 13)
  - Dairy cows along road, 2 prints and 9 4x5 negatives (Box 6, 13)
  - Sheep in a field, 2 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Naturalized citizens group, 3 4x5 negatives (Box 13)
  - Wilsonville ferry (Box 6)
  - Little girl with apples in John Hancock's orchard near Salem, Oregon, 3 prints (Box 6)
  - Close-up of Spitzenberg apples in John Hancock's orchard near Salem (Box 6)
  - Flats of blackberries fron Alderman Farms, 2 prints (Box 6)
  - Chevrolet farm pickup truck, circa 1949 (Box 6)
  - Cabbage field (Box 6)
  - Closeup of pears on tree in orchard near Medford, Oregon (Box 6)
  - Pig in a field (Box 6)
  - Rows of sweet corn (Box 6)
  - Two young boys picking strawberries, Salem, Oregon (Box 6)
  - Camellia Society? gathering (Box 6)
  - Christmas party, 5 prints (Box 6)
  - Group of people attending a reception?, 3 prints (Box 6)
  - Church in Salem? (Box 6)
  - Small businesses on street, Salem? (Box 6)
    Includes Unique Cleaners, H&H Furniture Company, and Stone Piano Company.
  - O.L. Wellman & Son, Richfield Oil Co. agents in Mt. Angel, Oregon (Box 6)
  - Removing underground storage tank near the Capitol, Salem (Box 6)
  - State office building (Box 6)
  - Truck on snow covered road (Box 6)